<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fan&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://dearxxj.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Fan&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 20:36:43 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dearxxj.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning HTSlib (1)</title>
      <link>https://dearxxj.github.io/post/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 20:36:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearxxj.github.io/post/5/</guid>
      <description>In the past week, I&amp;rsquo;ve been adapting my own HiC pipeline to the 4DN recommended pipeline. One critical step is to convert hundreds of read-paired BAM files generated by my old pipeline to pairs format. 4DN consortium provides a tool, bam2pairs, for this task. It&amp;rsquo;s basically a Perl script that calls Samtools to read a BAM file and output targeted fields. Because the pair format suggests the columns to be sorted by chr1-chr2-pos1-pos2, bam2pairs then calls Linux &amp;ldquo;sort&amp;rdquo; to perform four times of sorting based on these four columns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exact string matching algorithms: Boyer-Moore and KMP</title>
      <link>https://dearxxj.github.io/post/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 20:42:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearxxj.github.io/post/4/</guid>
      <description>String matching algorithms are used in lots of scenarios such as searching words in a text file, or locating specific sequences in a genome. I&amp;rsquo;ve heard of KMP algorithm long time ago, but don&amp;rsquo;t have a chance to implement it by myself (just lazy). It seems that KMP is not widely used in genomics field, but instead another algorithm, Boyer-Moore, is taught more often in computational genomics classes. I recently find a great online tutorial on computational genomics by Ben Langmead @JHU (link).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Similarity measurement of two sets of TADs</title>
      <link>https://dearxxj.github.io/post/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 22:26:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearxxj.github.io/post/3/</guid>
      <description>Months ago I had this question of comparing TADs from two Hi-C experiments in my research. TAD is short for topologically associated domains, discovered by Dixon et al [1] in 2012, which are regions in the genome that interacts more frequenctly with regions in the domain than outside. The goal of comparing TADs from two Hi-C expriments is to search for differentially interacting regions under two conditions to tease out regions that react to the conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How does number of threads affect mapping time in BWA MEM</title>
      <link>https://dearxxj.github.io/post/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 19:42:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearxxj.github.io/post/2/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using BWA MEM a lot recently for mapping short reads from whole genome sequencing or HiC experiments. Mapping high coverage sequencing data is a time-consuming task. The easiest way to accelerate, especially on servers, is to use multiple threads which is done by adding the -t flag. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen my labmates use 20 threads, 32 threads, or 40 threads. There seem to be no offical suggestions on the number of threads that would make the mapping fastest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://dearxxj.github.io/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 23:43:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearxxj.github.io/page/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a PhD candidate in Bioinformatics @PennState. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in applying all sorts of bioinformatic magics to solve cutting-edge biological problems!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello from dearxxj</title>
      <link>https://dearxxj.github.io/post/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 10:52:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearxxj.github.io/post/1/</guid>
      <description> Hello World! </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>