<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>statistics on Fan&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://dearxxj.github.io/tags/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in statistics on Fan&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 01:06:12 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dearxxj.github.io/tags/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Eigenvectors from Eigenvalues: A python implementation</title>
      <link>https://dearxxj.github.io/post/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 01:06:12 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearxxj.github.io/post/7/</guid>
      <description>A paper titled &amp;ldquo;Eigenvectors from eigenvalues&amp;rdquo; has recently sparkled heated discussions in Chinese communities on Wechat. This paper, co-authored by Peter Denton, Stephen Parke, Terence Tao and Xining Zhang, introduces a new method for calculating eigenvectors from solely eigenvalues. Some bloggers even describe this method as a revolution to traditional textbook method for calculating eigenvectors. I&amp;rsquo;ve never heard of this method before and wanted to give it a try to see if it is valid from a computational aspect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Similarity measurement of two sets of TADs</title>
      <link>https://dearxxj.github.io/post/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 22:26:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearxxj.github.io/post/3/</guid>
      <description>Months ago I had this question of comparing TADs from two Hi-C experiments in my research. TAD is short for topologically associated domains, discovered by Dixon et al [1] in 2012, which are regions in the genome that interacts more frequenctly with regions in the domain than outside. The goal of comparing TADs from two Hi-C expriments is to search for differentially interacting regions under two conditions to tease out regions that react to the conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>